GEORGIOS DRIVAS

MSc Biologist

Email: georgios.c.drivas@outlook.com Mobile phone number: 647-846-9478

Home address: 145 Glen Albert Dr, East York, ON M4B 1J1

EDUCATION

2014-2015: M.Sc. Course in Biotechnology for Environmental Sustainability at the Edinburgh Napier University, Scotland, UK

• Finished my studies first in grades out of a class comprised of 12 students. I was also frequently asked to guide my fellow students through their experimental processes and my overall performance has been awarded with the Edinburgh Napier University Medal for outstanding academic achievement

2006-2012: B.A.Sc. degree from the Department of Biological Applications and Technologies, University of Ioannina, Greece (5 year course equivalent to 300 ECTS) with a grade of 7.29 out of maximum 10 (72.9%)

• I have involved with different activities during my undergraduate studies like volunteering in the BirdLife of Greece for a period of almost 2 years, in order to participate in the monitoring of the populations of *Falco naumanni* in the area of Epirus, photographing the wildlife of Vikos canyon in Greece

Additional Education

2008-2009: Acquired the International Diploma in IT Skills Standard (ECDL) from the University of Cambridge.

• I have acquired the basic training in the use of computer for the programs: Microsoft Office Word, Microsoft Excel, MS Internet Explorer, Windows, Microsoft Power Point and Microsoft Access

Languages:

- Greek- Native language
- English

2009 ECPE Certificate of Proficiency in English – University of Michigan

SKILLS

- > Experience in performing bacterial cell cultures using various media and different carbon sources
- ➤ Able to perform enzymatic assays using laccases enzymes and measure initial reaction rates and the activity of enzyme reactions
- Previous experience in the usage of Gas Chromatography (GC) equipment and PCR technique
- ➤ Able to perform techniques like MPN and Membrane Lauryl Sulphate Broth to assess the concentration of coliforms in surface waters
- Calculate concentrations and dilutions required to prepare stock, general solutions and standard curves
- Know how to perform PCR technique

- Know how to work under sterile conditions and apply GLP rules
- Able to process data and design standard curves and graphs in excel program plus ability to calculate and incorporate Standard Error (SE) in the graphs
- Skilled at communicating scientific work in the form of presentations or posters
- Considerable experience in using the computational biology tools of Scopus and NCBI databases and in general searching of articles
- Considerable IT skills
- Skilled at achieving deadlines and working in laboratories with multicultural colleague

WORK EXPERIENCE

- 26/7/2017 28/11/2017: Telephone call salesman at COSMOTE
 - I was part of a group of 14 people with the task of promoting and selling through telephone landlines and mobile phone subscriptions to former customers of COSMOTE. The average score was 2-3 contracts a day with a minimum of one (1) a day and an overall of 70% return of the former customers
- 26/1/2017 1/6/2017: Call salesman at the Quality Call Sales Center of Thessaloniki

 Sourcing potential clients for various large telecom networks (primarily Vodafone) while negotiating new contract conditions for clients with an average of 3-4 contracts a day and 60-65% of successful contracts
- 7/3/2016 7/12/2016: Private in the health services of the Greek army
 In the context of conscription, I was commissioned with the duties of Master sergeant of the personnel and I was responsible for the unit's daily program and the issuing of the day-off permits for the conscribed soldiers
- Feb. 2013 Jun. 2014: National Pan-Hellenic University Science Tutor
 Preparing middle school and high school pupils for their examination periods in the subject of mathematics, chemistry and biology
- Nov. 2011- Apr. 2013: Printing factory assistant in Grafikes Technes Entechno Ltd.
 I was working as an assistant for the preparation of leaflets, magazines, wedding invitations and books with a production (example) as much as 50,000 leaflets a day sometimes over 10 hours of work a day

VOLUNTEERING AND OTHER ACTIVITIES

Oct. 2013 – Sep. 2017: Planner of extra-curricular activities for preschool and primary school learners.

• I was volunteering for almost 4 years in the Children's Museum of Thessaloniki along with a team of educators and teachers in the preparation of learning activities for kids, in the fields of geography, science, physics, chemistry, biology and sociology not only for educational but also for pleasant plus constructive time for the children

Sep. 2009 – Jul. 2011: Enumerator of bird populations.

- Volunteered as enumerator of the populations of *Falco naumanni*, *Pica pica* and *Neophron percnopterus* in the ecosystem of the lake Pamvotis and Vikos canyon in Ioannina city and prefecture of Epirus, Greece
- Jul. 2008 Sep. 2011: Organizer of cycling excursions in the University of Ioannina cycling team (POSPI).
 - Part of a team of students that helped POSPI to be established in the University of Ioannina and organize monthly or weekly excursions to different remote areas of Epirus or to the city of Ioannina, for cycling

Sept. 2013 - Jun. 2014: Latin Dances learner.

• Being passionate about Latin dances I have spent almost a year learning how to dance Bachata, Chacha, Rumba and even swing and I have also participated in festivals with the highlight the participation in breaking of the world record in the biggest Salsa Rueda de Casino in the world on the 06/01/2014

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Patila M., Taha A., Heider-Kentrou S., <u>Drivas G.</u>, Pavlidis I., Katapodis P., Stamatis H. (2011). Catalytic behavior of redox enzymes in deep eutectic solvents. Congress of Applied Biotechnology 25-29 September 2011 Berlin, Germany, In abstract Book
- 2. Pavlidis I.V., <u>Drivas G.</u>, Dados A., Taha A.A., Papastephanou Ch., Katapodis P., Stamatis H. (2011). Fungal laccase production and their application for the degradation of aromatic compounds. 12th XVI Congress of European Mycologists Halkidiki Greece 19-23

 September 2011
- 3. <u>Drivas G.</u>, Taha A.A, Pavlidis I.V., Patila M-V, Dados A, Katapodis P. Stamatis H. (2011). Biocatalytic degradation of environmental pollutants using laccase madiator systems. 4th Congress of Mikroviokosmos, 21-23 October 2011
- 4. Bukas N., Stara K., Jacob F., Vlahopoulos K., <u>Drivas G.</u>, Christodoulaki A. (2010). The Kestrels (*Falco naumanni*) in Ioannina:

 Preliminary results of monitoring and conservation actions. 5th Pan-Hellenic Congress of Ecology, Patra, Greece 7-10 October 2010 In Abstract book (in Greek)
- 5. <u>Drivas G.</u>, Stainsby F., Vaughan H. (2017). Relationship between cell surface hydrophobicity and foaming stability in *Gordonia* strains isolated from activated sludge. 6th Environmental Congress of Macedonia, Thessaloniki, Greece 5-7 May 2017 (in Greek)

PROFILE

Since childhood I have been very interested in the science of Biology resulting in my studies in the Department of Biological Applications and Technologies in my native country, Greece. The 5-year course, together with a one- year dissertation under experimental laboratory conditions, has endowed me with the multiple necessary tools to work as a biologist. Understanding the necessity for constant self-improvement, I decided to undertake my MSc studies at Edinburgh Napier University (ENU) in order to increase my knowledge and critical thinking as a researcher in Biology and to be given the chance of working in an inspiring, competitive, international, environment, something deemed essential for every bioscientist. The MSc course in Biotechnology for Environmental Sustainability has so far provided me with extensive knowledge in preparing a business plan, bioinformatics tools analysis of DNA and protein sequences, critical appraisal of various biotechnologies and alternative approaches used to remediate polluted terrestrial and aquatic environments. I have also been given the chance to further increase my knowledge in cell culture techniques and evaluate the role and application of microorganisms in the sustainable production of biofuels, biopolymers and other commodities and also to gain experience in techniques like Western blot and competent cells preparation. Also I have acquired considerable experience in software like photoshop, FastStone image viewer, Microsoft excel, powerpoint and word. I am also very interested in cycling and use it as an extension of my childhood and as a way of satisfying my eco-conscience. Regarding the conscription I have served in the 71st Airmobile Brigade of the Greek Army, where I was commissioned with the duty of the Master sergeant of the company. I also participate in Latin dancing, having performed in various Festivals with highlight the participation in the braking of the Guinness World Record in the biggest Rueda de Casino on the 1/6/2014. With my knowledge and previous experience I believe that I would be an asset to your company so it is with great honour and appreciation that I submit this CV for consideration.

REFERENCES

Professor Haralambos Stamatis

Deparment of Biological Applications and Technologies University of Ioannina 45110, Ioannina, Greece tel +30-2651007116

fax: +30-2651007343 e-mail: hstamati@uoi.gr

Senior Lecturer Fiona Stainsby

School of School of Life Sports and Social Sciences, Sighthill Campus Edinburgh Napier University
Edinburgh, Scotland, UK, EH11 4BN
tel +44(0)131 455 3304

e-mail: f.stainsby@napier.ac.uk

Dr Halina Vaughan

Lecturer in Environmental Microbiology Programme Leader: MSc Biomedical and Biomolecular Suite School of Life, Sport and Social Sciences, Sighthill Campus Edinburgh Napier University Edinburgh, Scotland, UK, EH11 4BN

tel: 0131 4553488

e-mail: <u>H.Vaughan@napier.ac.uk</u>